## **Thought**Works®

## Yogesh Avi Dhamija Senior Consultant Developer

Yogesh is a Senior Consultant at ThoughtWorks Ltd. with five years of software delivery experience, both as part of small startups and large teams in established corporate environments. He has primarily worked in ecosystems surrounding Java, JavaScript, Python, and PHP. He has an interest in getting some experience in data analysis.

## ThoughtWorks Experience

#### Fortune 500 Airline, based in the US (December 2019 - March 2020)

Yogesh was brought on as a full stack developer among a large team of roughly 50 people. Over the course of the next year, he worked as part of a single large team, as well as multiple smaller teams. He became an outspoken advocate of good coding and domain design practices, and took ownership of particularly troublesome pieces of the application architecture. He also helped with client onboarding, and took efforts to improve the development process by working with account leadership on the account's Virtual Health Check survey.

## Other Experience

#### Software Developer, Noble Markets (January 2018 - October 2018)

Worked as part of an agile startup team to develop trade settlement software. Was involved in designing the architecture and API. As part of a larger team, worked to expand software to manage settlement of cryptocurency assets.

#### Software Developer, Arcane Strategies (October 2016 - February 2017)

Led the effor to build a custom DevOps platform to automate project deployments and audits, integrate with BitBucket and Jira, etc.

#### Software Developer, Blue Fountain Media (May 2015 - October 2016)

Worked as part of a large team on various in-house and client web projects (including NYU.edu). Helped extend development assistant software to manage internal complexities of the business. Built an automated style-guide generator for web designs.

#### Technical Intern, Cornerstone Capital Inc. (November 2014 - April 2015)

Maintained, and added features to main company website (WordPress), while developing a secondary website for a short term initiative (HTML/CSS/JavaScript, PHP, MySQL). Facilitated technical matters in a business context, such as domain name transfers.

#### IT Administrator, Dr. Alan Andrews Dermatology (May 2014 - August 2014)

Designed, developed, and launched a website for the practice (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) with a simple custom CMS backend (PHP). Managed office FTP server and backup system.

### Skills

• Languages: Java, JavaScript (TypeScript), Python, PHP, SQL

# **Thought**Works®

- Frameworks: Spring, React, Angular, Tornado, Laravel
- Tools: Docker, Flyway, Numpy, SQLAlchemy, Redis, AWS
- Methodologies: BDD, TDD, CI/CD
- Miscellaneous: Expository writing and editing, fluent in English and Hindi

## Education

• BS in Computer Science, focus in Cybersecurity from NYU Tandon School of Engineering (Graduated 2018)